# **THOMAS GUNAWAN S**

Jl. Jendral Sudirman No.110 Semarang • +62 851-5634-1089 • thomasgunawannn@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/thomasgunawannn/

#### **SUMMARY**

Senior Software Quality Assurance Automation with over 4 years of experience in the banking industry. Highly skilled, innovative, and an excellent communicator within team environments. With a bachelor's degree in Informatics Engineering, I bring comprehensive expertise to every project I undertake.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## PT. BANK NEGARA INDONESIA (Persero) Tbk.

### **COE's Testing Management Services Officer Assistant Manager**

June 2023 - Present

- Develop and maintain a comprehensive automation testing strategy, including test automation frameworks and tools
- Manage and mentor a team of 18 automation engineers to ensure efficient and effective testing
- · Collaborate with development teams to ensure software is built with automation testing in mind
- Design, develop, and execute automated tests to ensure software meets specified requirements
- Analyze test results and provide regular progress updates to stakeholders
- Develop and maintain test data and test environments to support automation testing
- Developed and implemented test automation process, resulting in a 150% increase in testing execution speed.
- Stay up-to-date with new software testing technologies and tools and recommend appropriate solutions for the team to implement
- Continuously enhanced testing standards and procedures to optimize process efficiency and effectiveness.

# **Software Quality Assurance Automation Assistant Manager**

March 2023 - May 2023

- Develop and maintain a comprehensive automation testing strategy, including test automation frameworks and tools
- Manage and mentor a team of 16 automation engineers to ensure efficient and effective testing
- · Collaborate with development teams to ensure software is built with automation testing in mind
- Design, develop, and execute automated tests to ensure software meets specified requirements
- Analyze test results and provide regular progress updates to stakeholders
- Develop and maintain test data and test environments to support automation testing
- Stay up-to-date with new software testing technologies and tools and recommend appropriate solutions for the team to implement
- Continuously evaluate and improve the automation testing process to ensure efficient and effective testing practices

# **Software Quality Assurance Automation**

March 2021 - February 2023

- Oversaw the execution of manual tests for API, mobile, and web-based applications, ensuring thorough validation of software functionalities and compatibility.
- Developed and maintained test documentation, including test plans, test cases, and test reports, providing clear insights into testing progress and results
- Led and mentored a team of testers to ensure the delivery of high-quality software solutions.
- Managing resources for testing activity
- · Prioritizing and scheduling testing activities in regards to source code dependency
- Participated in project meetings, offering insights on testability, potential risks, and testing scope to drive successful project outcomes.

## PT. Mitra Integrasi Informatika

#### **Quality Assurance**

March 2021 - February 2023

Site PT. BANK NEGARA INDONESIA Pejompongan

• Developing Automation using UFT – web and mobile based applications.

## Project:

- Automation Website Keagenan (UFT)
- Automation Mobile Banking (UFT)
- Automation API Management (UFT)
- Automation Website Digisales (UFT)
- Automation Website Bni Credit Card (UFT)
- Automation Mobile SMS Menu (UFT)
- Automation Mobile Keagenan (UFT)

# **Application Developer**

June 2020 - February 2021

Site PT. BANK NEGARA INDONESIA Pejompongan Project :

- Development TQCApp on Scenario Test Menu (PHP, CI)
- Daily Report Monitoring TQCApp (scheduler, python)

# PT.PLN (Persero) Distribution of Central Java & DIY

### **Junior Programmer**

**April 2018 – July 2018** 

I'm an Intern at PT. PLN (Persero) Distribution of Central Java & DIY. It focuses on Building Source for multiplatform which helps Client to create Source based on their request.

Job description:

- Collecting data and processing data
- · Script writing using xamarin product
- Lead a team of 5 people

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Universitas Dian Nuswantoro**

**August 2015 - October 2019** 

Bachelors' degree, Informatics Engineering

• GPA: 3.26 of 4.00

## **Terang Bangsa Christian Semarang**

**July 2012 - June 2015** 

Television broadcasting technology

# **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

- Skills: Highly organized and efficient, Ability to Work in a Team, Creative Problem Solving, Automation Engineer
- Certifications: RPA Developer Foundation, Certified Application Security Engineer .NET, ISTQB® Certified Tester Foundation Level, ISTQB® Certified Tester Foundation Level Agile Tester, Api testing with katalon, Web UI Testing With Katalon: Low-code Journey, Pioneering Generative AI in Test Automation with Katalon